<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mohamed Hamoud</title>
    <link>https://mohamed-hamoud.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Mohamed Hamoud</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://mohamed-hamoud.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mohamed-hamoud.com/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mohamed-hamoud.com/cv/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mohamed-hamoud.com/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mohamed-hamoud.com/research/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;research&#34;&gt;RESEARCH&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;monetary-policy-surprises-and-the-term-structure-of-equity-yields&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=5160318&#34;&gt;Monetary Policy Surprises and the Term Structure of Equity Yields&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Job Market Paper&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt; This paper provides a new perspective on monetary policy transmission through financial markets. To do that, I analyze the impact of monetary policy surprises on the term structure of equity, using data from dividend futures markets to directly measure changes in maturity-specific risk premia and expected dividend growth. I find that monetary policy affects asset prices beyond its direct impact on risk-free rates: a 25-basis point surprise change in risk-free rates leads to a 25–50 basis point shift in equity risk premia and expected dividend growth. Notably, this impact is time-varying and significantly stronger in low-interest-rate environments, which is consistent with reach-for-yield behavior by investors. To identify the specific channels through which policy operates, I use a novel method to extract multiple, economically interpretable factors from asset price responses to policy announcements. The findings show that the documented effects on risk premia and expected dividend growth are driven specifically by the component of monetary policy surprises that moves short-term risk-free rates, rather than by components affecting long-term rates or investor risk sentiment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mohamed-hamoud.com/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mohamed-hamoud.com/teaching/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;teaching&#34;&gt;TEACHING&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;University of Zurich, Switzerland&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Advanced Financial Economics (&lt;em&gt;Assistant to Prof. Yucheng Yang&lt;/em&gt;, 2024-2025)&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Recipient of &lt;strong&gt;Award for Excellence in Teaching&lt;/strong&gt; 2024&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Advanced Financial Economics (&lt;em&gt;Assistant to Prof. Felix Kübler&lt;/em&gt;, 2021-2023)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Middle East Technical University, Turkey&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Introduction to Econometrics II (&lt;em&gt;Assistant to Prof. Ozan Eruygur&lt;/em&gt;, Fall 2017/2018)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Macroeconomic Theory II (&lt;em&gt;Assistant to Prof. Kağan Parmaksiz&lt;/em&gt;, Spring 2015/2016)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
